<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Regulation on NRG.fyi  Fuel Your Knowledge</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/regulation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Regulation on NRG.fyi  Fuel Your Knowledge</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/regulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Up Private Finance for Clean Energy in Emerging and Developing Economies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/financing/private-finance-for-clean-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/financing/private-finance-for-clean-energy/</guid>
      <description>This intend to be a summary post of the “Scaling up Private Finance for Clean Energy in Emerging and Developing Economies” published by the IEA and IFC The Emerging Markets and Developing Economics (EMDEs) group contains the following territories: Africa, Developing Europe, Eurasia, Latin America, the Middle East and South and Southeast Asia.&#xA;In EMDEs there are 775 million people that lack access to electricity and 2.4B that lack access to clean cooking fuels.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The energy Security Scenario</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/global-energy/the-energy-security-scenario/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/global-energy/the-energy-security-scenario/</guid>
      <description>This is a summary of the Energy Security Scenarios report made by Shell.&#xA;Shell created 3 different energy scenarios - Waves, Islands and Sky 1.5. Each of these was built around possible approaches to climate change action as the world emerged from the COVID-19 pandemic.&#xA;Waves - Waves assumed that society would prioritize repairing the economy. In Waves this focus on wealth pushes other societal and environmental pressures into the background, until their relative neglect provokes backlash reactions.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
