<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Energy Storage on NRG.fyi  Fuel Your Knowledge</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/energy-storage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Energy Storage on NRG.fyi  Fuel Your Knowledge</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/energy-storage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Power System Flexibility</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/grid-managment/power-systems-felxibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/grid-managment/power-systems-felxibility/</guid>
      <description>Energy Transition and need for flexibility.&#xA;There is no denying the fact that electricity is crucial for the world economy to thrive in this and the coming centuries. The demand for electricity increases not only because the human population increases, but also because the social-economic activities of humans are rapidly shifting from manual processes to automated processes, which are essentially driven by electricity. Therefore, electricity becomes inevitable for the sustainability of modern civilization because it has found its way to the root of many human establishments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ERCOT – Energy storage market</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/energy-storage/energy-storage-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/energy-storage/energy-storage-market/</guid>
      <description>Background on ERCOT&#xA;ERCOT manages the flow of electric power on the Texas Interconnection that supplies power to more than 26 million Texas customers – representing approximately 90% of the state&amp;rsquo;s electric load. As the independent system operator for the region, ERCOT dispatches more than 680 generating resources to reliably deliver power to customers over more than 46,500 miles of transmission lines. The performance of the markets in ERCOT is essential because those markets coordinate the commitment and dispatch of generating resources, manage flows over the transmission network, and establish prices that guide participants’ decisions in the short and long-term.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Battery energy storage use cases and outcome revenues streams</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/energy-storage/battery-energy-storage-use-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/energy-storage/battery-energy-storage-use-cases/</guid>
      <description>Energy storage has been around for a long time. Alessandro Volta invented the battery in 1800. Until recently, Batteries used to provide power at those locations where no grid connection is present, like for starter motors cars, mobile phones, laptops and other electronic devices or for emergency power or computer servers. With the last innovations in the energy storage industry, it is clear that energy storage technology and solutions will become crucial element in our life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Virginia Clean Energy Act</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/renewable-energy/the-virginia-clean-energy-act/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 15:43:48 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/renewable-energy/the-virginia-clean-energy-act/</guid>
      <description>According to the US EIA (Energy Information Association), current Virginia’s energy production stand on 8.5GW. 53% from Natural Gas, 31% from nuclear power, 10% from coal fueled and nearly 7% from Renewable Energy (RE).&#xA;On April 12, 2020 , Governor Ralph Northam signed the Virginia Clean Energy Act (VCEA), to accelerate Virginia’s transition to a clean energy environment.&#xA;The VCEA sets Virginia on the path for being 100% carbon free by 2045.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
