<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NRG.fyi  Fuel Your Knowledge</title>
    <link>https://nrg.fyi/</link>
    <description>Recent content on NRG.fyi  Fuel Your Knowledge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://nrg.fyi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://nrg.fyi/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 21:38:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nrg.fyi/about/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;NRG.fyi is an independent view about the renewable energy transition started in the previous decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NRG.fyi is created by Ofer Haiat and independent financial expert in renewable energy with proven global experience in natural gas, geothermal , solar, wind and energy storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ofer’s wide ranging career started with Israel Natural Gas lines, and governmental Israeli company who was in charge of the design , construction and operation of the high pressure infrastructure of natural gas , following the substantial foundings started late century and continued into early 2000’s. Among his roles , Ofer was responsible for the company taarif set by the government and created a cross continent financial transaction to support the financing needs of the infrastructure construction through international financial institutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After his journey in INGL Ofer joined Ormat Technologies (ORA) where he led the economics departments, creating cross organization processes to improve the financial budget and forecast performance. In addition he led the company&amp;rsquo;s global insurance portfolio through engaging the London and Houston market and dealt with significant and complex insurance claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017 , Ofer joined Viridity Energy Solutions, a subsidiary of Ormat, as their CFO , based in Philadelphia, PA , where he led the merger with Ormat and took the company transition into the energy storage market in North America through strategic plan and concentration in the utility scale stand alone energy storage projects in selected ISO/RTO’s in North America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2022 , Ofer has been acting as the CFO of Doral Europe , leading the financial and operational needs of the company in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NRG.FYI  created to be a place where energy stake holders (consumers, developers, financiers, off-takers and more) can join and use ideas and thoughts about the energy transition process, its innovations , news and developments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All opinions and other content in the blog should be seen as a recommendation for investment or any other action.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future energy storage and distribution</title>
      <link>https://nrg.fyi/post/energy-storage/future-energy-storage-and-distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nrg.fyi/post/energy-storage/future-energy-storage-and-distribution/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Future energy storage and distribution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is no longer a secret, nor a great insight, that we are in a
revolutionary era in terms of the energy industry. Many technologies ,
greener and cheaper are implemented , a lot of assets we uses are being
electrified
(&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meticulousresearch.com/product/electric-vehicle-market-5179&#34;&gt;EV&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;
, heating solution) and more and energy , in general becomes more of
commodity than an production resource.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that development, new challenges and limitations arise and create
risks for industrial, commercial, and residential uses and processes.
Our current power grids weren&amp;rsquo;t designed for the challenges they have
today - from EV&amp;rsquo;s to renewables, climate change and urbanization, so the
grid needs to be upgraded constantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To support grid distribution limitations, there is a need to improve and
create more solutions in the field of distribution and energy storage.
Energy storage is essential for the transition to a decarbonized economy
based on renewable energy sources, and energy distribution needs to be
smarter and more resilient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the fast implementation of EV&amp;rsquo;s, there will be a need to support
the EV&amp;rsquo;s needs in terms of charging and electricity. As of today, most
of the needs are local, and can be resolved through local applications
such as microgrid or even home battery charging stations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of distribution, we should expect development in the low
voltage network controls. In leveraging the power of distributed
intelligence, which features continuous insight analytics, and control,
utility companies can redefine what is possible with low-voltage network
management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, energy distribution systems are used as a hub through a single
source, power station, that can be either coal, gas, nuclear, hydro,
solar or wind. That energy is then distributed through a high-voltage
grid before being converted to low-voltage at the consumer end using
substations. In the future, while we continue to have the large-scale
energy system, we will see an increase in power generated at the edge of
the network through micro power stations, solar, wind and all forms of
renewables. This will be complemented with battery technologies to store
when needed. To implement this change requires a new grid distribution
and operational system for the major utility companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the following
&lt;a href=&#34;https://infrastructurereportcard.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Energy-2021.pdf&#34;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt;,
Over the period between 2017-2021, transmission and distribution and
reliability-focused pipeline investments have increased, and outages
have declined slightly. Annual spending on high voltage transmission
lines grew from $15.6 billion in 2012 to $21.9 billion in 2017, while
annual spending on distribution systems &amp;mdash; the &amp;ldquo;last mile&amp;rdquo; of the
electricity network &amp;mdash; grew 54% over the past two decades. Utilities
are taking proactive steps to strengthen the electric grid through
resilience measures. However, weather remains an increasing threat.
Among 638 transmission outage events reported from 2014 to 2018, severe
weather was cited as the predominant cause. Additionally, distribution
infrastructure struggles with reliability, with 92% of all outages
occurring along these segments. In the coming years, additional
transmission and distribution infrastructure, smart planning, and
improved reliability are needed to accommodate the changing energy
landscape, as delivery becomes distributed, and renewables
grow[.]{dir=&amp;ldquo;rtl&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Batteries expected to be used for short-term storage while thermal and
mechanical storage will be used for industrial heat and electricity for
mid-term storage and electrolyzes will turn excess power from renewables
will turn excess power from renewables into green hydrogen that can be
stored long term and turned into electricity or transferred to other
sectors of the economy as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the 3 trends who impacts the energy value chain:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://peggysmedleyshow.com/a-primer-on-clean-energy&#34;&gt;Renewables&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;ndash; technology around renewables is becoming more efficient in terms
of solar panels, wind farms, heat pumps, safe nuclear, and more.
Availability across the whole value chain &amp;ndash; from large utilities to
business and consumers- is critical, and this can enable
self-generation and provide additional energy back to the grid when
surplus is generated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Batteries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digitalization/Modernization&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; Transformation of the energy
sector through virtualization will require robust, scalable, and
reliable communications infrastructure to enable monitoring and
control leveraging the power. For instance, AI can enable energy
systems to make intelligent decisions about where, how, and when
they consume power in real-time. Edge compute platforms can extract,
store, and utilize data at scales, supported by AI accelerators and
automated processes , to schedule , manage , and automate the use of
renewable energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Value of Energy storage in Europe</title>
      <link>https://nrg.fyi/post/energy-storage/the-value-of-energy-storage-in-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nrg.fyi/post/energy-storage/the-value-of-energy-storage-in-europe/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Value of Energy storage in Europe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Energy storage has been deemed one of the missing links of the energy transition for quite some time now. After the vast deployment of standalone storage assets, which tirelessly (and swiftly) respond for duty when the grid needs it, the long-awaited next phase of renewables-plus storage is finally approaching the mainstream!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term ‘renewables-plus-storage colocation’ has climbed the ladder in the renewable’s vocabulary, particularly in the merchant renewables sphere. But combining two business models requires the resolution of multiple riddles. What is the optimal use-case of the hybrid set-up? What’s the optimal revenue streams strategy when there are competing interests between the two assets? How does the industry model a cost-benefit analysis to evaluate an investment decision?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The value of flexibility, not only for individual assets, but for the entire electricity system is widely recognized. On one hand, the ability to bid into the market and deliver grid services contributes to tangible ‘value creation’ for storage assets. Overall, policy and regulation players in each country have operated with different gears on that front, in the sense that value creation in each market differs. There’s a wide push for more and more jurisdictions to get up to speed with route-to-market visibility to encourage further deployment. &lt;a href=&#34;https://energy.ec.europa.eu/topics/markets-and-consumers/market-legislation/electricity-market-design_en&#34;&gt;The EU’s landmark Electricity Market Design&lt;/a&gt; proposed reform comprises the ultimate testament to the increased ambitions on a regional and member state level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, ‘value capture’ is the tough job of how to tap such value and convert it into realized revenue. This is where tools like optimization agreements, contractual arrangements, and Hybrid PPAs fall into place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interest in the asset class is growing exponentially both by policy and regulation (value creation) but modelling the value of storage for an investment case (value capture) is a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; When it comes to monetization of energy storage assets, it’s really the billion -dollar question to underpin the entire business case. The valuation aim is no different than any other infrastructure investment: investors need to understand the asset’s risk-return profile, its expected revenues and estimated internal rate of return (IRR) to understand whether the investment is worth pursuing. But with energy storage assets, performing this task is not as straight-forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the beginning of the energy transition, the risk profile of renewables attracted financiers like pension funds, institutional investors, and lenders due to the asset mirroring the characteristics of ‘core infrastructure’ assets: low-return low-risk asset profiles which are able to generate stable yields. Since then, not only have the risks profile of renewables evolved, but new asset classes with different risk profiles were deemed necessary and required calibration of investment strategies. And yes, energy storage was the first new asset class to rock the boat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monetizing strategies for storage are ever evolving. Starting from grid-level opportunities, grid operators and regulators are creating a plethora of routes to market in the form of grid services for energy storage (and particularly fast responding battery storage) to support the technology’s deployment and eventually take advantage of its competitive edge: quick flexibility to replace services that used to be provided by retiring thermal plants, and tackle supply/demand imbalances from increased renewables penetration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the most critical revenue streams exist through imbalance markets, such as the UK’s Balancing Market (BM) daily auctions, Capacity Markets (CM) or regulation ancillary services such as Fast Frequency Response (FFR), for example UK’s Dynamic Containment (DC), and Automatic Frequency Restoration Reserve (aFRR) auctions. Such opportunities gave birth to robust business models for standalone storage assets. A prime example is the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the standalone energy storage concept matured, market players started looking at such assets from a complementary angle, that of co-location. Asset-level opportunities are centered around the idea that storage is primarily improving the performance – and therefore investment returns – of renewables through mitigating the risks deriving from their inherent intermittency nature. Profile shaping comprises a prime example, tackling the effects of cannibalization in the spot markets. The latest mega trend in the renewables-plus-storage sphere is in Hybrid PPAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focal level of standalone storage asset is indeed grid services. However, when it comes to co-location, it’s pivotal to note that the two focal levels, grid- and asset-level opportunities, are not mutually exclusive. The combination of value creation from grid-level services alongside optimization of asset-level revenues encapsulates the driver behind the seeking of the colocation promising land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Value Stream&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Comments&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Balancing service&lt;/strong&gt; – accessible for SA and co-loc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Balancing authorities across Europe have the heavy responsibility of managing the physical aspect of the grid in real time, ensuring that there is a balance between supply and demand. Each country has different mechanisms in place to perform this task, creating services for various generations of technologies to monetize their contribution. It’s deemed a key route-to-market for storage assets.For example, in the UK - Operated by National Grid ESO, the Balancing Mechanism (BM) is the operator’s primary tool to balance supply and demand on the network in real time. &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regulated Markets&lt;/strong&gt; – FCR, FFR – an opportunity for SA projects, but also co-loc through optimization agreements for the storage part of the hybrid project&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Short-term ancillary services enabled the number one competitive advantage of batteries to shine: fast response to grid needs in seconds. The nature of such services is to adapt their requirements depending on what is needed the most. For example, the cadence of auctions is adapting, and so are the rules of participation or the required volumes. Therefore, it’s not merely the strike price that is uncertain, but also the very existence of the service. The opportunistic thesis of such services put the seeds of a flexible mindset in storage asset owners and set the foundations of the famous ‘revenue stacking’ approach. Not one revenue stream is enough to create a long-term revenue plan to enable project or debt financing, so the aim has been to tap opportunities when they arise and feel comfortable with it. Optimization companies became some valuable partners, aiming to create as much revenue visibility as possible to their clients, and being in charge with the day-to-day bidding strategy of the assets through optimization agreements.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sales in spot markets&lt;/strong&gt; – price arbitrage can be performed by SA while profile shaping with the same benefits can be achieved by co-loc assets&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Outside the ‘services’ world, energy storage is also a participant in the wholesale spot markets. The aim is to take advantage of spot market volatility in the day-ahead markets, storing energy when spot prices are low, and selling at peak hours; aka price arbitrage and profile shaping for co-located assets. The wider the average daily wholesale spread, the better. Because such value stream is not a limited participation regulated service, it&amp;rsquo;s deemed as the most durable long-term revenue stream&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capacity Markets&lt;/strong&gt; – prime route to market offering some long-term revenue visibility through specific contracts. Can be accessed both from SA and co-loc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;In the UK - The scheme offers 1-15 year contracts for generation or demand-side response (DSR) units to financially incentivize their availability. The more sought after 15-year contracts are only reserved for new-build assets and comprised the success factor behind the first debt financings for battery storage assets. The upwards trajectory of the clearing price over the past auctions has surprised even the most optimistic observatory, rendering the revenue scheme a highly valuable both for new and existing assets. Othe EU countries - France, Ireland, Poland, Belgium, and Italy followed suit in setting up capacity mechanisms, which is deemed a large enabler of new storage assets to receive financing and connect to the grid. More countries are set to follow, with a prime example being Greece. The design, participation rules and payment mechanism differ from country to country, so participants need to confirm the bankability of such contracts in each region&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Portfolio level risk management&lt;/strong&gt; - the benefits of standalone storage assets and co-located ones can be equally quantified on a portfolio level&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;As renewables portfolios are growing, so are the risks that portfolios are exposed to. Price risk due to merchant exposure, capture risk due to cannibalization, and volume risk due to intermittent are some of the core ones. Flexible assets (such as energy storage or gas engines) and technologies (such as hydro) often help dilute risk exposure through diversification of capabilities. Such a value stream can only be measured through quantitative analysis either on a portfolio level (which could include standalone storage as well) or on individual asset level (only if storage and renewables are co-located) on an overall portfolio level, as it’s not a direct revenue stream such as the abovementioned. In a high pricing environment, imbalance risk for renewables also becomes notable, and through storage co-location imbalance costs could turn into revenue.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hybrid PPA&lt;/strong&gt; - a contractual arrangement leveraging benefits both for the grid- and asset-level, only available to co-located assets&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;With a Hybrid PPA, the idea is to get the best of the two worlds: potentially generate revenues through grid services, while improving the investment returns of the renewable asset. The first financial-benefits touchpoint of considering co-locating a renewable asset with storage is the cost savings from the shared grid connection. Such cost savings, as well as saturation in the ancillary service markets, increased cannibalization risk for renewables and volatility in the wholesale markets incentivizing profile shaping of intermittent renewables, comprise factors driving market players to explore the co-location model overall. The maturity of tangible contractual arrangements and the emergence of Hybrid PPAs make the co-location consideration even more attractive. How the two assets will communicate will be dependent on the contractual details. With a Hybrid PPA, it’s possible to have a physical asset to manage the different types of PPA structures, practically turning storage into a physical hedge to complement the financial hedge of the renewable asset. At the same time, another option would be for the two assets to operate virtually independently, with a renewable PPA for the generation, and an optimization agreement for storage. Or adding a price premium to the energy produced from the renewable asset by valuing-in the flexibility which allows better risk management of the energy. &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revenue streams and use-cases for energy storage assets are multiple. Yes, energy storage is a Swiss-army knife multitasker, but eventually a decision needs to be made as to which business model will prove the one which best underpins each case. After the screening phase of available opportunities comes the time for modelling different scenarios, which we have identified as a core challenge in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The energy Security Scenario</title>
      <link>https://nrg.fyi/post/global-energy/the-energy-security-scenario/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nrg.fyi/post/global-energy/the-energy-security-scenario/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The energy Security Scenario&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a summary of the Energy Security Scenarios report made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.shell.com/energy-and-innovation/the-energy-future/scenarios/the-energy-security-scenarios.html&#34;&gt;Shell&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shell created 3 different energy scenarios - Waves, Islands and Sky 1.5. Each of these was built around possible approaches to climate change action as the world emerged from the COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Waves&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;Waves&lt;/strong&gt; assumed that &lt;strong&gt;society&lt;/strong&gt; would &lt;strong&gt;prioritize repairing the economy&lt;/strong&gt;. In &lt;strong&gt;Waves&lt;/strong&gt; this focus on wealth pushes other societal and environmental pressures into the background, until their relative neglect provokes backlash reactions. This prompts rapid action to address global emissions but, even though the world achieves net-zero emissions, it comes too late to meet the stretch goal of the Paris Agreement – to limit global average warming to 1.5°C above pre-industrial levels by the end of this century. &lt;strong&gt;This scenario shows late, but fast decarbonization&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Islands&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;Islands&lt;/strong&gt; assumed that &lt;strong&gt;security becomes the priority after COVID-19&lt;/strong&gt;. In &lt;strong&gt;Islands&lt;/strong&gt; a new emphasis on nationalism threatens to dismantle the post-war geopolitical order and co-operation is limited. &lt;strong&gt;Competition between nations&lt;/strong&gt;, however, &lt;strong&gt;means technological advances&lt;/strong&gt;. Innovations are adopted, infrastructure is renewed and eventually the world does still reach net-zero emissions. &lt;strong&gt;The goal of the Paris Agreement is missed&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;This is late and slow decarbonization&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Sky 1.5&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;Sky 1.5&lt;/strong&gt; set a fixed goal of achieving the Paris Agreement and worked backwards from that point to explore how that could happen, considering the global situation in the early 2020s. Using this normative approach, in &lt;strong&gt;Sky 1.5&lt;/strong&gt; there is a post-pandemic focus on health and public well-being that results in high levels of co-operation towards mutually beneficial aims. This is accelerated decarbonization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In February 2022, the fragile post-Cold War global order cracked apart when Russia invaded Ukraine. There had already been worries about the supply of fossil-fuel energy, but the invasion made it clear how dependent society is, collectively, on traditional fuels like oil and gas. As nations respond, the world is collectively plunging into the security mindset that dominates &lt;strong&gt;Islands.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new situation created 2 new sub scenarios:  &lt;strong&gt;Archipelagos&lt;/strong&gt; (as relevant to Islands) and &lt;strong&gt;Sky 2050&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;strong&gt;Archipelagos&lt;/strong&gt; scenario seeks to follow a possible path from where the world was in 2022, while &lt;strong&gt;Sky 2050&lt;/strong&gt; starts with a desired outcome of: net-zero emissions by 2050 and global warming limited to 1.5°C by the end of the century and works backwards to explore how that outcome could be achieved. Working backwards to the realities of 2022 means that, while &lt;strong&gt;Sky 2050&lt;/strong&gt; does make many stretching assumptions, there is no expectation of halving emissions by 2030 as required by the Glasgow Climate Pact from COP26.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To analyze how countries will react to the recent geo-political changes, the report creates 4 types of country profile as in the below table. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Profile&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Energy supply&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Energy prices volatility&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Region&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Green Dream&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Highly vulnerable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Highly vulnerable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;EU&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Innovation Wins&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Not vulnerable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Highly vulnerable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;USA, UAE&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Great Wall of Change&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Not vulnerable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Not vulnerable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;China&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Surfers&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Vulnerable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Vulnerable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;India&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/YkeI59OV5dX91NX-E2-b-0b7Dj8OxY4yomvtKlcGEiEo8lawVkdx887aQXAg-4_LX2fCTQHW5x1XPCr5IV0rXxgMVX3x7SCztG2XN5MWjwDpGs4bTdcNMC07zMqKD06oNnIx7x9y5EXBa1FaGmaXDQ&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The need for energy security&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the end of the Soviet Union, many had assumed that the forces of globalization and liberalization would prevail. Multiple developments seemed to support this view, including interconnected supply chains, international travel, and global cultural events. Other sources of optimism included the spread of social media, the unifying effects of digitalization and a shared concern over climate change. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beneath all of this, however, huge cracks have opened in the global order with growing doubts about the future of globalization itself. The signs pointing to trouble ahead have been present for some time. There has been a rise in nationalism, populism, and growing inequality within and between states, as well as a failure to deliver significant climate finance. The main examples are the trade war between the US and China, the Brexit and difficult relationships between Australia and China. With the war in Ukraine, the world has seen the threat to use nuclear weapons, the undercutting of international institutions such as the UN and interruptions in the supply of energy and food that are affecting the whole world. In the coming years, there appears to be little prospect of any return to the former world order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Paris Agreement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of the Paris agreement is:” Holding the increase  in the global average temperature to well below 2°C above pre-industrial levels and pursuing efforts to limit the temperature increase to 1.5°C above pre-industrial levels, recognizing that this would significantly reduce the risks and  impacts of climate change”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How close the world is to reaching 1.5°C of warming is best described in terms of what is known as the “carbon budget”. The ongoing rise in global temperatures has a roughly linear relationship to the amount of CO2 emissions built up in the atmosphere over time. This means it is possible to estimate what sort of temperature rise is likely from a given amount of CO2 emissions in the atmosphere. Knowing how much CO2 results in each temperature rise, means society can estimate how much CO2 can be emitted before the world hits 1.5°C of warming. This is the carbon budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These dynamics around the carbon budget leave the world with only one option if it is to achieve 1.5°C. If society exceeds its budget, then it must make up the difference later. It can do so by removing CO2 from the atmosphere to balance the excess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pathways which exceed the carbon budget but then make up the difference in subsequent years, by removing CO2 from the atmosphere, are referred to as overshoot pathways. In these pathways the global average surface temperature overshoots the desired goal, but eventually returns to that level. &lt;strong&gt;Sky 2050&lt;/strong&gt; is an overshoot pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This overshoot pathway leads to a conclusion that carbon capture, carbon removal and carbon storage will have to play important roles.  This set of technologies comes in many shapes and forms as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Industrial CO2 capture at a facility such as a chemical plant. This involves passing a stream of waste gases over a material which binds to the CO2 and prevents it from reaching the atmosphere.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Direct capture of CO2 from the atmosphere (DAC).  This involves sucking air over a material which binds to the CO2 and removes it from the atmosphere. Very large quantities of air must be processed for this technology to deliver a meaningful result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geological storage takes the CO2 captured at an industrial facility, or through DAC, and places it in a geological formation some 2-3 km below the surface. This is permanent storage away from the atmosphere and so removes the CO2 from the natural carbon cycle. In this way it either compensates for, or prevents, CO2 from being added to the atmosphere by the combustion of fossil fuels or chemical processes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increasing the carbon held in the land system through activities such as reforestation and soil restoration.  This removes CO2 from the atmosphere.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capturing CO2 from power plants fueled by biomass and permanently storing the CO2. This is known as bioenergy with carbon capture and storage (BECCS). It indirectly removes CO2 from the atmosphere.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leapfrog development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important element of securing the goal of the Paris Agreement is an effective leapfrog over the fossil fuel era – cutting out the use of fossil fuels entirely. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some nations have the potential to leapfrog because they start from such an energy poor position. Rather than fueling their countries’ development by burning fossil fuels, they move directly into widespread electrification and low-carbon sources of electricity generation. Apart from global climate benefits, bringing forward electrification with renewables has significant domestic advantages. These benefits include improving local environmental quality, increasing energy access, and reducing import dependence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;Sky 2050&lt;/strong&gt;, and to a large extent in &lt;strong&gt;Archipelagos&lt;/strong&gt;, the countries do not enter the fossil fuel era to the extent that others have (although many still consume biomass, such as wood) and instead move straight to electricity-based energy technologies such as wind and solar. They adopt these technologies at only a slightly slower rate than nations of other archetypes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A successful leapfrog – which involves electrifying the economy, accelerating the adoption of renewables, and investing to integrate these new energy sources into each nation’s energy system – requires three things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Powerful effective policies&lt;/strong&gt; - These policies incentivize electricity use sector-by-sector (such as transport, buildings, and industry). The policies also work to decarbonize the power sector and include both targets for the uptake of renewables and subsidies to support their adoption. The world is already seeing action of this nature starting in countries like South Africa and Indonesia. In addition, government policies remove institutional and regulatory barriers to renewable deployment. One example would be to ensure that the low cost of renewable electricity is reflected in the prices that customers pay. Another example would be to speed up planning processes and regulation reforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Worldwide renewable acceleration&lt;/strong&gt; - Critically, the cost of renewables must fall, alongside the cost of technologies that integrate intermittent renewable generation into the power grid. Falling costs can drive further deployment and improve confidence in renewables-based systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sufficient Finance&lt;/strong&gt; - This means governments and international institutions, such as multilateral development banks, need to find innovative ways of working with private sources of capital to provide adequate funding streams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The impact of leapfrog development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The potential power of the leapfrog phenomenon tends to be overlooked. In part this is because most forecasts have systematically failed to anticipate the declining cost of solar and wind generation. This failure means the speed of renewable deployment is also typically underestimated. In addition, not enough weight has been given to the cost reductions that are likely as more and more renewable systems are rolled out around the world: society will learn as it goes and find better and more efficient systems and techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sectoral and societal trends&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The chemical industry transforms.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since World War II, the demand for non-energy products made from oil – such as petrochemicals (including plastics), fertilizer and bitumen – has grown steadily. The world’s use of chemicals is extremely diverse: they are used in many products that provide comfort and convenience, including packaging, clothing, home insulation and foams for furniture. Less obvious to many, they are also essential to products used for sanitation, preserving foods, treating diseases, and increasing crop yields. Innovation into new advanced materials – and new ways of using them – is constantly increasing the usefulness of these products in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So central have non-energy oil products become that demand for them has grown at the same pace as the global economy (in terms of GDP). Demand growth in developing countries runs even faster than GDP, as lifestyles catch up. In rich countries, the evidence suggests that per capita demand is slowing down and may have reached a peak for some products. However, predictions of a shift to less material-intensive growth have not yet occurred at large scale. Attempts to move towards traditional materials like metal and glass often run into the challenge that they can come with higher carbon footprints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With rising incomes in non-OECD countries, demand continues to grow. Growth in richer countries starts to plateau, albeit at different rates. Plastic waste in nature, growing concerns on microplastics and the industry’s increasing share of global CO2 emissions led to a wide range of environmental challenges. Addressing these is not easy for the industry: it is a highly complex sector due to its diversity across consumers, products, technology, by-products, and international trade. The industry’s production facilities can also last 60 years or more, often locking in old technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A growing share of bio-based chemicals emerges through a mix of new policies and a higher willingness from consumers to pay a premium. Many such chemicals will be based on different molecules than those that emerged from the oil-based feedstocks that are common today. In addition to bio-based feedstocks, there is a move to bio-degradable products. These are focused on applications where the lack of recycling options means there is a high risk of these products remaining for a long time in nature, such as microplastics. The fertilizer industry is the first to move at large scale to products made from green hydrogen – made by using renewable energy to split water molecules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Energy efficiency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The security-first mindset that dominates following the Russian invasion of Ukraine, combined with the high price of energy, brings energy efficiency to the top of agendas. This is a factor across both scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When fossil fuels dominate the energy mix, energy use drives emissions. This means that limiting the use of energy can help limit emissions. In addition, by keeping overall energy use as low as possible the growth of new energy supplies can displace a greater proportion of the legacy fossil fuel-based energy system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Energy use can be limited by two methods. Firstly, people can choose to use energy in more efficient ways – by driving smoothly and limiting speed, for example. Secondly, products and processes that use energy can be designed to use it more effectively – cars can be designed so that the amount of energy they need to drive 1 kilometer comes down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electric vehicles convert around 80% of the energy they take from the grid into power at the wheels. This means that if the electricity for an electric vehicle comes from a renewable energy installation, which generates electricity without losing energy through combustion, the overall efficiency of the system is around 80%. The exact figure depends on transmission losses, electricity storage and other factors. The picture is less good for electric vehicles if the electricity is produced by burning coal or natural gas. If fossil fuels are the source of the grid power going into an electric car, the overall efficiency is around 25-40%. Conventional internal combustion engine vehicles convert less than a third of the energy stored in petrol to power at the wheels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond electric vehicles, other major step changes involve appliances and heating in homes and buildings. While most appliances are already electric, moving from cooking on flames to electric cooking significantly improves efficiency. Natural gas cooking hobs are about 40% efficient, whereas whole electric-coil and standard smooth-top electric hobs are around 70% efficient. The latest induction hobs are more than 80% efficient. Cooking with biomass, like wood, is likely to be less efficient than natural gas, although in certain circumstances where home heating is incorporated, this may not always be the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the efficient use of energy to heat or cool buildings can be improved both as a step change – by introducing technologies such as heat pumps – and progressively through an active insulation program. Under ideal conditions, an electric heat pump can transfer 300% more energy than it consumes. In contrast, a high efficiency gas furnace is about 95% efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A transport revolution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Road passenger&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future of road passenger vehicles shifts rapidly to a single solution: battery electric power. No space emerges for any other solution as manufacturers abandon the development, then production, of vehicles with an internal combustion engine. Business models throughout the passenger transport sector rapidly move towards electric vehicles. The energy efficiency of electric vehicles means that total energy demand in this sector falls even as vehicle numbers grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Road freight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The road freight transition also includes a shift towards electricity. This starts with light vans, municipal trucks, and service vehicles, before spreading into medium-haul trucks. But the high-energy density of molecular fuels remains critical for very heavy-duty applications and long-haul, high-capacity road freight. Biofuels and, much later, synthetic fuels based on CO2 directly captured from the air, contribute to a lower carbon footprint for the sector. From the late 2020s, hydrogen fuel-cell vehicles emerge as the preferred solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aviation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aviation remains reliant on liquid hydrocarbon fuels, with no alternatives emerging at scale until the 2040s. Battery electric planes – with the electricity used to turn propellers – make their first appearance in the 2030s on very short commuter routes. Jet turbine planes, burning hydrogen as a fuel, start to appear on medium-haul routes in the 2040s. The major shift comes in the formulation of jet fuel, with sustainable aviation fuels taking market share from the 2020s onwards. This starts with biofuel being mixed with kerosene. In time, the cost of capturing CO2 from the air using direct air capture (DAC) fall, and this allows for the cost-effective production of synthetic hydrocarbon fuels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shipping&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; In the 2020s and 2030s, the shipping industry experiments with a number of options to reduce its carbon footprint. These include biofuels such as bio-methanol, liquefied natural gas (LNG) and hydrogen (either directly using hydrogen as a fuel, or in the form of ammonia). In the mid-2030s, however, the industry settles firmly on the hydrogen-based solution, working in close co-operation with shipbuilders, fuel suppliers and key bunkering ports. Almost all ships constructed after this time have fuel systems that use either hydrogen or ammonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-ttIkNShDfXCkNviUhcC1zNDCe3Yw0b907MyxkHXKiVb28phOYGwiW5907jZs4Gb1S4VMWxnzElA0hf3H8Z3yEPWeCPO__szJVbkAoDP1a94-p4DJ4ht5sWd_hj_MlToswS9cfujNwEtV6DV3GZr_g&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/13dLPeMHxdpbwmC2XjNpl07ZSGnNmX3Dcu_-gflVNQY-T5kFCfg4mWxPITT_eM3WknRdUgExhKMQ3BY_z3TmQuot6O7DbVdiUumyOvSv6Xut8Zv1YbNjTKXqdEgjpPlMr6gvPUg4oEtSfKZ_luigPA&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/UqAfL4yNTa0vZjXIZ3H7i9WxQ4g3WJchNrZze93Ej5XfeTeph5kWUgW8BoakF2LpkPf7aG9nRaOTGasx-KgYcvyrFNwtI5ksIcnfhgIztbXCplDiz2V-SRZnh30vP6GHw773diJExv5R61JaGdlUiw&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ERCOT – Energy storage market</title>
      <link>https://nrg.fyi/post/energy-storage/energy-storage-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nrg.fyi/post/energy-storage/energy-storage-market/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background on ERCOT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ERCOT manages the flow of electric power on the Texas Interconnection that supplies power to more than 26 million Texas customers – representing approximately 90% of the state&amp;rsquo;s electric load. As the independent system operator for the region, ERCOT dispatches more than 680 generating resources to reliably deliver power to customers over more than 46,500 miles of transmission lines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The performance of the markets in ERCOT is essential because those markets coordinate the commitment and dispatch of generating resources, manage flows over the transmission network, and establish prices that guide participants’ decisions in the short and long-term. Although natural gas prices fell 23% on average in 2019, causing electricity prices to fall in most of the country’s wholesale markets, real-time energy prices rose 32% in ERCOT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Load in 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Total ERCOT load in 2019 increased 2% from 2018, an overall increase of 880 MW per hour on average. In June, July and August, there was a 6% increase from 2018 in the number of cooling degree days in Houston. Cooling degree days is a metric that is highly correlated with summer loads. Summer conditions in 2019 produced a new record peak load of 74,820 MW on August 12, 2019, surpassing the previous record of 73,473 MW on July 19, 2018. The South, Houston, and West zones experienced varying increases in peak load ranging from 0.4% in the South zone to more than 11% in the West zone. In contrast, the North Zone consumed 3.4% less at peak than in 2018. The level of peak demand is important because it affects the probability and frequency of shortage conditions, as well as the quantity of resources needed to maintain reliability. However, in recent years, peak net load (demand minus renewable resource output) has become more highly correlated with the probability of a shortage condition. Generating Resources Approximately 4.9 gigawatts (GW) of new generation resources came online in 2019, the bulk of which were wind resources with total nameplate capacity level of 4.7 GW, and an effective peak serving capacity of approximately 1,250 MW. The remaining capacity additions were: 80 MW of combustion turbines, 50 MW of solar resources, and 30 MW of storage resources. There were 550 MW of retirements in 2019: 470 MW of coal and 80 MW of wind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Generation levels in 2019 were mixed by the following: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The generation share from wind has increased every year since 2004, reaching almost 20% of the annual generation in 2019, up from 19% in 2018 and 17% in 2017.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The share of generation from coal continues to fall, down to just over 20% in 2019.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The falling coal output was replaced by natural gas generation, which increased from 44% in 2018 to 47% in 2019.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We expect these trends to continue because of historically low natural gas prices, making gas fired resources increasingly more economic than coal resources, and the continued growth of zero fuel cost resources, like wind and solar. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wind Output&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investment in wind resources has continued to increase over the past few years in ERCOT. The amount of wind capacity installed in ERCOT approached 27 GW at the end of 2019. ERCOT continued to set new records for peak wind output in 2019. On January 21, wind resources produced a record 19,672 MW instantaneously. On November 26, wind provided nearly 58% of the total load, also a new record. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increasing levels of wind resources in ERCOT have important implications for the net load served by the non-wind fleet of resources. Net load is defined as the system load less wind and solar production, and the range is getting larger. The difference between highest and lowest net load MWs was even more pronounced in 2019 than 2018. Wind output displaces the total load needed to consume the minimum production from baseload units, particularly at night. The output of wind resources results in only modest reductions of the net load relative to the actual load during the highest demand hours, but much larger reductions in the net load in the other hours. The importance of net load in ERCOT was illustrated during the week of August 12 when the highest prices did not correspond to the highest loads, but rather to the highest net loads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ERCOT UNIQUE MARKET STRUCTURE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Texas’ unique electric market structure facilitates choices by energy customers and producers that contribute to grid reliability in ways that differ from every other region in North America. ERCOT relies on market competition and price signals to assure that real-time electric supply matches demand. Some question the wisdom of trusting an “energy-only” market and issue warnings every summer of impending blackouts in the August heat. To date, however, the combination of high prices and falling resource costs have increased the amount of generation installed in ERCOT and the availability of the generation fleet during tight market conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ERCOT’s experience has shown that Texas’ market structure supports electric reliability in an economically effective and environmentally sustainable way. Over the past 18 years, wholesale electric competition within ERCOT system has attracted extensive new investment in renewable and fossil resources, energy storage and price-responsive demand. These investments have leveraged technology innovations, including the replacement of inefficient natural gas and coal plants with highly efficient natural gas and extensive wind and solar generation capacity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distributed energy resources, such as photovoltaic solar and storage, and demand-side measures, such as energy efficiency and automated and price-responsive demand, can respond to prices as well as to grid management signals. In a time of rapid demand growth and uncertain supply, these assets should be used to de-risk the electric system by reducing peak load and ancillary service needs (fast ramping, in particular). This reduces the burden and cost of assuring adequate supply and flexibility services and protects customers while enhancing system and community resilience. All of these resources can be coordinated and integrated with advanced monitoring, forecasting, analytics, communications, and controls to integrate and balance demand with supply for reliable, affordable and sustainable electric service&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buyers and sellers within ERCOT use bilateral contracts and energy-only spot markets with scarcity pricing for electricity transactions. Power producers in ERCOT only earn revenue from the sale of energy and ancillary services. They decide whether to keep or retire existing plants and build new plants based on the competitiveness of those plants relative to prevailing energy prices and forward market prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reserves are capacity that is available to be used, but will not provide energy until called on by its owner or the grid operator. Unlike other regions, ERCOT does not require a mandatory reserve margin.27 28 Rather, reserve margins in ERCOT fluctuate based on generators’ decisions about whether to build or shutter a power plant in the region, and customers’ decisions on how much energy to consume and when. Both supply and demand decisions are driven by economic price signals: low real-time prices indicate that energy is cheap and over-supplied, while high prices mean that energy is valuable&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of North America’s electric operating regions have planning reserve margins (the proportion of projected availability of anticipated electric generation and load management resources to meet forecasted customer peak load) ranging from 13 to 97% over projected customer load.29 Customers in these regions essentially make advance payments, whether through capacity market charges or through rate-base payments to bundled utilities, to assure the availability of what policymakers deem to be adequate capacity levels during annual or seasonal peak periods. In these regions, the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) limits shortage- or scarcity-related energy price caps to $2,000 per MWh, and price spikes in those regions are viewed as market problems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The premise for setting planning reserve margins has historically been that grid operators should have sufficient generation in excess of load that generation shortfalls (rotating outages or full blackouts) should occur no more than one day in every ten years. These outdated assumptions ignore the fact that demand is no longer absolute; many customers now have the capability to manage their electricity usage through active or automated means in response to price signals or grid conditions. Furthermore, since over 99% of actual customer outage minutes occur due to failures of transmission and distribution (mostly affected by severe weather events)30 rather than insufficient generation, it is likely that incremental additions of generation capacity will have little impact on customer outages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prices method in ERCOT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Since Ercot is energy only market, there is no capacity compensation for electricity generators. To cover this lack of compensation and to encourage new investments of new generators , from any kind, the market desgn in a way that in times of shortage or the the load get closer to the maximum market capacity , genreators are getting paid very high price per hour, with a cap of $9,000/MWh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;These&lt;/strong&gt; High prices signal to new generators that they can recover their operating and capital costs. They also motivate retail electric providers to sign contracts directly with generators to lock in predictable prices and shield themselves against future price spikes and contract with retail customers to provide future demand response when needed. And power contracts help generators finance new plants and demand aggregators finance new demand management projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The demand curves&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an effective economic market there is an active supply and demand curves, wherein suppliers can decide how much of the product they want to offer at any price, and customers can decide how much they want to consume at each price. The interaction of these supply and demand curves sets product prices. In markets where many active suppliers compete, such as ERCOT, the market-clearing price will be a time-series of short-run marginal costs, reflecting the cost to produce the last unit consumed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Classic microeconomic theory holds that rational consumers will want more of something if its price decreases and buy less of it when its price rises. In the case of electricity, however, some electricity uses (such as medical ventilators or an active integrated circuit production line), are so valuable that the user is indifferent to the price of electricity and will consume the same amount at almost any price. Traditionally, most electricity consumers have no real-time information about the price of electricity because they are buying flat-priced energy, and their providers never reveal either the real-time cost of electricity or the amount of electricity that the user is consuming. These limitations create a steep, near-vertical demand curve that is relatively unresponsive to rising electricity prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ERCOT’s demand curve has become fairly price-responsive because many customers have the opportunity to access information on their electricity usage and access to retail electric rate options that encourage using less electricity in times when it costs the most. ERCOT estimates that during the peak load week of August 12-16, 2019, when load was very high and three actual or near-critical peak loads occurred, at least 17% of load was exposed to real-time energy prices, 58 and customers reduced their peak load use by 1,600 up to 3,100 MW&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ninety percent of ERCOT’s electric meters are advanced meters that measure and record use data in 15-minute or faster time increments.60 This means that it is theoretically possible for almost 7 million ERCOT electricity users to monitor their electricity usage in near-real time. 61 Texas regulators are presently considering rule changes for real-time electricity use data access that could greatly compromise customers’ and third-party energy managers’ ability to access real-time electricity usage data and act upon that information promptly with price- or use-responsive energy management actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ERCOT has robust retail competition. About 70% of electric residential, commercial and industrial customers have left their default or distribution-affiliated electric provider for service from 116 competitive Retail Electric Providers (REP).63 In any month in 2018, between 275,000 to 440,000 ERCOT customers shopped for a new REP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many electricity customers can participate in retail time-of-use rates and demand response programs. REPs in ERCOT offer over 300 rate plans and products; 64 while many rate plans offer fixed rates (a single price per kWh over an extended contract period), others offer time-varying priced electric rates. These include time-of-use and real-time-pricing rates that increase prices during late afternoon peak use periods, critical peak pricing, and options that offer “free nights and weekends” programs that incent customers to move their energy use away from costly daytime energy use to times when abundant, cheap wind energy is available.65 In 2018, 1,254,734 ERCOT end-use customers were enrolled in some type of retail time-of-use or price-responsive rate, representing up to 1,415 MW of load that might respond to some form of time-based electric retail prices.66 These include REP customers and customers served by municipal utilities, such as Austin and San Antonio, that are not open to retail competition. Such retail programs affect how much ERCOT electric customers, in aggregate, are willing to pay for electricity at various times and price levels and thus affect market-clearing electric prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ERCOT’s transmission and distribution utilities also offer limited load management programs. Many programs pay end-use customers to take a limited number of curtailments on summer weekday afternoons. Over 250 MW of load participates in these programs. These curtailments are dispatched for grid operational reasons and may be deployed during a Level 2 Energy Emergency Alert.68 Some municipal and cooperative utilities also deploy Conservation Voltage Reduction to lower voltage and thus lower demand by 1-3% along selected feeders during peak load conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “4CP” mechanism is one of the most impactful demand-shifting mechanisms in ERCOT. Cost allocation rules allocate ERCOT-wide transmission costs based on distribution utilities’ and large customers’ individual electric demands on the four 15- minute intervals when ERCOT’s maximum coincident peak (CP) demand occurs. Therefore, many of ERCOT’s REPs and portfolio managers alert customers when a peak demand day is expected so the customer can cut its energy usage to reduce the level of the next year’s demand charges. This helps the REP manage its energy portfolio and costs. ERCOT estimates that about 2,475 large customers cut or shifted their peak demand by between 920 and 1,781 MW during 4CP and “near-4CP” events in 2018, materially changing the level and time of peak demand.70 Estimated 4CP demand in August 2019 ranged from 946 to 2,136 MW on the maximum load and near-coincident peak days.71 This demand avoidance is not a response to energy prices, but rather an effort to avoid demand charges (presently set at $53.58 per kW for transmission cost recovery). 4CP days occur on the hottest days of the year but are not often coincident with the highest energy prices&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large industrial customers and aggregated smaller customers have the option of participating in ERCOT’s ancillary and reliability services markets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsive Reserve Service (RRS) is the dominant option for loads. Loads controlled by high-set under-frequency relays are paid if they are called to provide frequency response. Over 3,000 MW of load is qualified to provide RRS. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regulation Service and Fast Responding Regulation Service are attractive options for storage resources, which act as generation resources when injecting energy into the grid and controllable load resources when charging. The number of resources qualified to provide these services will increase as ERCOT’s installed storage capacity grows. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-Spinning Reserve options for load resource participation are under development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ERCOT can call on Emergency Response Service (ERS) customers to meet grid emergency conditions. ERS has 10-minute and 30-minute ramp requirements that can be provided by loads and small generators. The August 15, 2019 ERS deployment delivered almost 750 MW of load reduction over a 1.5 hour period, exceeding the required reduction level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ERCOT issues Energy Emergency Alerts (EEAs) when remaining operating reserves fall below 2,300 MW. An EEA triggers ERCOT’s use of various levels of Emergency Response Services, REP and other calls for voluntary conservation, and actions such as distribution utility implementation of Conservation Voltage Reduction. Two EEAs were issued during August 2019. In each case, a suite of actions taken on the customer side – response to 4CP signals, distributed generation and customer energy management – and REP demand response chasing high prices and EEA-associated voluntary conservation produced load reductions from 1,800 up to up 3,100 MW during peak hours. 74 These load reductions reduced electricity demand by over 3% in some of the highest-priced hours of 2019 and were essential for maintaining reliable grid operation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customer-owned distributed energy resources also affect ERCOT customer demand and load shapes. ERCOT registers larger facilities (1 to 10 MW) and cannot effectively track unregistered (smaller than 1 MW) distributed generation located on a customer’s site. At the end of 2018, ERCOT had over 1,300 MW of energy storage and solar, diesel, natural gas, and other generation connected at the distribution level, growing at over 60% per year. 76 Distributed solar PV alone is forecasted to reach 2,580 MW by 2024.77 ERCOT estimates that distributed generation across ERCOT increased net output by 150 to 200 MW during the August 12-16, 2019 peak periods&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the factors and programs above affect the balance between electricity supply and demand in ERCOT and the resulting market equilibrium prices, regardless of whether the demand or distributed resources are actively bid into the market or operate quietly behind the customers’ meter or the REP’s portfolio. Any non-market measure that affects the level of demand (such as population growth and temperature levels) and the availability of substitutes (such as energy efficiency and photovoltaics), customer price elasticity (such as through demand response) influences the equilibrium market price. If many customers gain the capability to see and respond to real-time electricity prices, their actions will affect market-clearing electricity prices. Though it is appealing to have demand and DER resources show up as active, quasi-supply bidders in the spot market, the rules and high entry costs of becoming active market participants may dissuade such participation and limit demand and distributed generation initiatives. This could harm, rather than enhance, ERCOT’s system reliability and resilience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Energy Storage in Texas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Nearly 24GW of wind capacity, ERCOT has seen the most power development in the US and is beginning to see an increasing push to add solar generation driven by tax credit availability rather than a state renewable portfolio standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approximately 90% of the Texas load is served through the ERCOT market, which set a record peak demand of 74MW on August 2019. More than 25% of generating capacity in ERCOT, as of January 2019 came from intermittent resources – 23.4% from wind and 2.1% from solar. The current interconnection queue provides an insight about the future generation which will be mixed by core intermittent, with 59 MW of solar accounting for 54% of the queue, 36,000 of wind accounting for 33% of the queue, 10GW of gas representing 9% of the queue, and 4GW of battery storage representing 4% of the queue. With this queues status and plan development, ERCOT will look like a ripe market for the storage energy developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the increase in less-expensive renewables sources comes a decrease in power prices. ERCOT West Hub on-peak real-time locational marginal prices have fallen into negative territory in five out of the last seven years as most wind – and more recently solar- is added across the sprawling open fields of west Texas. West Hub real-time prices have already fallen as low as negative 3 cents/MWh so far this year, something that typically happens later in the year. In 2016, West Hub real-time prices fell as low as negative $9.68/MWh in Q4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Energy storage capabilities provide a wide range of services to the grid in a single compact package. Storage deployment is still in the early stages relative to wind and solar. The main revenue streams that are the most attractive for battery energy storage project are the capacity, ancillary services and energy. However, the ERCOT market is an energy only market, so the capacity portion is not part of the formula to battery energy storage projects in ERCOT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the 2 other portions are not so beneficial yet for energy storage projects in TX. Texas does have market for FR, and some storage projects are participating. But this is all merchant too, and the returns are nowhere near as solid as in the early days of PJM’s battery boom. The small market is already getting saturated. That pattern had repeated everywhere else. Looking at the energy market structure and behavior, it looks like that the potential is there, with the ability of prices getting up to $9,000/MWh. The problem that the market is not too volatile, and the arbitrage opportunities are still low.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Battery energy storage use cases and outcome revenues streams</title>
      <link>https://nrg.fyi/post/energy-storage/battery-energy-storage-use-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nrg.fyi/post/energy-storage/battery-energy-storage-use-cases/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Energy storage has been around for a long time. Alessandro Volta invented the battery in 1800. Until recently, Batteries used to provide power at those locations where no grid connection is present, like for starter motors cars, mobile phones, laptops and other electronic devices or for emergency power or computer servers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the last innovations in the energy storage industry, it is clear that energy storage technology and solutions will become crucial element in our life. The ongoing transition we are experiencing with the higher shares of renewable and intermittent energy resources and distributed generation applications requires ways to store and release energy when needed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Energy storage has the potential to provide a wide array of benefits to the electric grid, and states across the country are increasingly considering statewide targets for the deployment of energy storage resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently there are 7 states who adopted storage procurement targets:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;California – 1,325MW by 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nevada – 1,000 MW by 2030&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oregon – 10 MWh by 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NY – 3,000 MW by 2030&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MA – 1,000 MWh by 2025&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NJ – 2,000 MW by 2030&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VA- 3,100 MW by 2035.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These procurement targets, set a confidence among market developers and financial institutes through their approach to develop and support the energy storage market in the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several use cases for energy storage divided mainly to ancillary services and load shifting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ancillary services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frequency control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voltage control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black start energy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Load shifting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hedge of energy sells commitment breach penalties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Energy arbitrage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Schedule stabilization – to avoid ramping up costs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capacity reserve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peak shaving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Energy storage cases can also be seen through major consumers groups &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The storage industry has been boosted by few successful completion of  non-recourse battery energy storage project financings and the increase in utility procurement of battery storage projects and products, as seen above. Private developers have recently closed hundreds of millions of dollars of financings for large battery projects. Moreover, utilities have procured hundreds of megawatts of utility-owned battery projects through EPC, BOT or similar contractual acquisition structures and have executed numerous contracts for battery project services and products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The successful development and financing of any type of energy or infrastructure project requires many different building blocks, including site control, permits, interconnection, regulatory exemptions, EPC, O&amp;amp;M, PPA/offtake revenue contracts, and others. Although each of these is important, the most critical issue is to ensure the viability and finance-ability of battery storage projects arise primarily in the area of dependable offtake revenues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Battery Storage Revenue streams:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capacity&lt;/strong&gt; – Energy storage projects could provide a utility an obligation for the projects readiness to charge/discharge from/to the grid when such services will be called by the utility. For this on-call service, the project will get paid based on a fix amount of dollars per MW, according to the project commitment. This structure is used in PJM and CAL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tolling agreement&lt;/strong&gt; – The energy storage tolling agreement provides the off taker (typically a utility) with capacity, energy and other products generated by a grid-connected, stand-alone battery project. As the “seller” under the agreement, the project sponsor is responsible for developing, owning, operating and maintaining the battery project, and retains technical operational control of the battery. As the “buyer” under the Agreement, the off taker typically exercises full authority to charge and discharge the battery, subject to the battery’s operating limitations and other agreed dispatch parameters. In addition, the off taker typically pays for and delivers all charging energy from the grid to the battery and acts as “scheduling coordinator” or “market participant” for the battery in managing its scheduling arrangements. The off taker pays the project sponsor a fixed (usually monthly) capacity charge for its right to utilize the battery’s capacity, and frequently a variable operating or “energy” charge for dispatches instructed by the off taker. The capacity charge may be subject to reduction for decreases in capacity, availability or efficiency of the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ancillary Services&lt;/strong&gt; – Ancillary services are used by the grid operator to balance the frequency of the grid and ensure there is enough reserve capacity to meet unexpected stress events. The project sells ancillary services to the market at spot price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Demand response&lt;/strong&gt; – various energy storage projects can aggregate into one source, like a virtual power plant, and provide the grid demand-response service in exchange for fixed payments. Demand response means shedding behind the meter load in response to a signal from the utility. The battery or other storage device may be used by customers for other applications when not providing demand response services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Demand charge&lt;/strong&gt; – also known as peak shaving. High electricity co consumers are paying extra charges on their electricity load at peak days. To avoid those charges, customers can have another source of energy (for the peak moments only) like a battery. That way, the customer will save the peak demand charges and the economic benefits will be split between the customer and the battery provider.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Energy Arbitrage&lt;/strong&gt; - simple as it sounds, an energy storage facility can use energy prices fluctuation and charge the battery when cost of electricity is low and discharge the battery and sell electricity when cost of electricity is high&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstracting the complexity of microgrids</title>
      <link>https://nrg.fyi/post/microgrid/abstracting-the-complexity-of-microgrids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nrg.fyi/post/microgrid/abstracting-the-complexity-of-microgrids/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It is not secret anymore, that the way we are using energy cause damage to our planet. In 2021 we expect to consume 40x energy compare to 1900.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Due to the global warming we will demand 3x energy by 2050 compare today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To adjust to the new energy reality, organizations are under growing pressure to participate in the globalization effort reduce emission and avoid global warming. Over the past decades the cost of electricity distribution increased by 50% in the U.S. In order to confront the global warming, states are setting mandates for 100% cleat electricity , covering nearly one-third of the U.S.C&amp;amp;I and companies are forecasted to see over $100B in annual losses from power outages through the end of the decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the solution will be to bring electric and digital together – Microgrid&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;DOE  a microgrid is a group of interconnected loads and distributed energy resources within clearly defined electrical boundaries that acts as a single controllable entity with respect to the grid. A microgrid can connect and disconnect from the grid to enable it to operate in both grid-connected or island mode.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traditional  centralized utility grid is a big interconnected network that takes energy from large far away energy generation paltforms and transmit it over long distances to consumers.As technologies andpolitics continue to evolve, communities and business can choose to supply their own enrgy locally by building their own microgrid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As energy become vermore critical n our daily live, Microgrids will enable us to shift from central power generation to local, flexible and reliable form of sustainable power and thermal energy &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microgrids won’t be a core part of the clean-energy transition until they serve all three grid needs — greener, more reliable, more resilient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, most microgrids around the world rely on diesel generators, which are polluting and loud, so they’re not very green. (In the US, the primary sources are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.grandviewresearch.com/industry-analysis/microgrid-market&#34;&gt;CHP and natural gas&lt;/a&gt;.) They only turn on once the grid is down, so they don’t help with day-to-day reliability. Of the three grid needs, most serve only resilience, and only for those lucky enough to be connected to one&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As basic as most of them are today, microgrids hold great promise for the future. Technology is rapidly expanding the possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Electricity use is becoming more controllable and adaptable, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.greentechmedia.com/squared/dispatches-from-the-grid-edge/how-billions-of-iot-enabled-devices-could-change-the-grid-edge&#34;&gt;as every system and appliance learns to communicate over the internet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small-scale and community-scale electricity generators are getting cheaper, cleaner, and more diverse; they now include solar panels, small-scale wind, efficient natural gas generators and fuel cells, CHP, and more.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Energy storage is also becoming cheaper and more diverse, from various kinds of batteries and fuel cells to thermal storage in hot water or ice. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://microgridknowledge.com/front-of-meter-microgrid-sonoma/&#34;&gt;The Stone Edge Farm microgrid in Sonoma boasts five separate forms of storage&lt;/a&gt;.) Every bit of new storage helps to smooth out the variations in solar and wind, allowing more to be absorbed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software, AI, and machine learning are enabling intelligent integration of all these diverse resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart design and software can create microgrids specifically designed to integrate distributed renewable energy, or microgrids designed to provide “six nines” (99.9999 percent) reliability, or microgrids designed for maximum resilience. There are even “nested” microgrids within microgrids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distributed microgrids present a business model challenge to investor-owned utilities and transmission systems as these microgrids are increasingly able to compete in wholesale energy, capacity, and ancillary services markets, and displace utility loads and utility revenue. Utilities are increasingly building their own renewable generation, often with a microgrid architecture to meet the demands for new generation and grid reliability required by regulators, but utilities are being asked to do much more than compete with distributed power. ISOs, RTOs, utilities, and regulators are working to transition electric grids to allow fair competition to provide reliable low-cost power. Utilities were once a natural monopoly. Now, they are being asked to help build out an efficient, workable, low-carbon distributed system, and figure out how they will fit into that system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arcweb.com/&#34;&gt;ARC Advisory Group &lt;/a&gt;market studies of microgrids and grid-scale battery suppliers show these markets growing, with large compound annual growth rates. The traditional grid hardware, software, and service providers are very strong suppliers to the microgrid market. Many smaller suppliers have also emerged in the nano-grid market for residential PV systems with battery storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worldwide, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.powermag.com/energy-at-a-cellular-level-battery-storage-shows-plenty-of-power/&#34;&gt;lithium batteries have established a strong lead in the market for grid-scale batteries&lt;/a&gt; in part by the economies of scale. PJM Interconnection, demonstrated that lithium batteries can be used effectively for grid frequency control applications. As the markets for frequency control get saturated, there are many other markets where new grid-scale battery applications can compete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, a grid-scale battery with a modern power inverter/converter is an instant microgrid all by itself. Coupling microgrids to meet demand-side flexibility is a problem that must be solved. This will require new technology, new regulations, and new business models, and the smart grid to perform new tasks it was designed to do but has never done before at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Electric Power Research Institute’s (EPRI’s) issued in 2018 &lt;a href=&#34;http://mydocs.epri.com/docs/PublicMeetingMaterials/ee/USNEA_FinalReport_Executive_Summary_3002013582.pdf&#34;&gt;the U.S. National Electrification Assessment report&lt;/a&gt; , describing the idea that effective integration of energy supplier and user networks can and will lead to more reliable, flexible, and affordable energy services&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The power industry has always had the choice to integrate the user side of the grid to reduce peaks and smooth loads. Pumped-hydro storage was built in some cases to avoid cycling nuclear plants; the new distributed generation grid also needs that type of operational flexibility. So, what is different now that we need to integrate to the demand side? The difference is the system now has unprecedented network communications, digital technologies, mobile devices, smart meters, smart grid standards, and the electrification of transport and building heating, ventilation, and air conditioning (HVAC). These enable far greater flexibility to adjust demand on the user side of the grid. While this is arguably the most complex systems integration problem society faces today, ARC believes all the technology needed to succeed is in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While natural gas has an important role to play, &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmi.org/insight/the-economics-of-clean-energy-portfolios/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Economics of Clean Energy Portfolios&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;—published in 2018 by the Rocky Mountain Institute (RMI)—warns of the high costs of a rush to gas generation. RMI provides business-model research to show renewable energy, including wind and solar, and distributed energy resources, including batteries, have fallen precipitously in price in the last 10 years. At the same time, developer and grid operator experience with these resources has demonstrated their ability to provide many, if not all, of the grid services typically provided by thermal power plants. This renewable electric generation is a major driving force for microgrids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electric grids are increasingly deregulated, but deregulation has a long way to go before small players can compete in all the markets where large generators or large loads currently do. Grids are already using local marginal pricing (LMP) to drive generation and loads, but this price is meaningless to small users. Even with smart meters and smart grid standards, small microgrids and nano-grid operations have not reached the point where they are driven by the real-time local price of power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More homes will have solar PV and batteries, electric vehicles, heat pump hot water heaters, and electric-driven HVAC systems, but how can homeowners with flexible loads will provide services to the grid?  How can they be compensated for the grid services they might provide? PV battery systems do not support power export, electric vehicles do not support V2G (vehicle-to-grid) or remote charging applications, heat pump hot water heaters do not support scheduling, end-users cannot buy Wi-Fi enabled residential circuit breakers that support grid price scheduling.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silent Cyber – What to look for</title>
      <link>https://nrg.fyi/post/risk-managment/silent-cyberwhat-to-look-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 15:43:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nrg.fyi/post/risk-managment/silent-cyberwhat-to-look-for/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As the world continues to advance technologically, the number of cyber-attacks has increased at an alarming rate. A study done by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.accenture.com/us-en/insights/security/cost-cybercrime-study&#34;&gt;Accenture and the Ponemon Institute&lt;/a&gt;, which researched 355 companies in 16 different industries, revealed that between 2014-2018 security breaches have increased by 67%, with an 11% increase in 2018 alone. On their third annual state of cyber resilience, Accenture and the Pnemone institute, found that 10.9% of organizations’ IT budget spent on cyber security, only 60% of the business ecosystem is protected by the cybersecurity program and 40% breaches reached out via this tour. 69% of the organizations in the study agree staying ahead of attackers is constant battle and the cost is unsustainable. Since 2013, companies such as Yahoo!, Marriot, MySpace, Under Armour, Equifax, Ebay, Target, and LinkedIn have each suffered data breaches of at least 100 million user accounts, with Yahoo! being the highest, at 3.5 billion accounts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Costs incurred by victims of cyber-attacks have increased exponentially. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.varonis.com/blog/cybersecurity-statistics/&#34;&gt;The average cost&lt;/a&gt; of a single cyber-attack now exceeds $1 million, and the average cost of a malware attack is $2.4 million. Total damages for cyber-crime are projected to reach $6 trillion annually by 2021. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.securitymagazine.com/articles/89734-average-cost-of-cyberattack-now-exceeds-1-million&#34;&gt;In a report by the Global Application &amp;amp; Network Security&lt;/a&gt;, 78% of businesses reported that they experienced a cyber-attack that either caused service degradation or a complete network outage. These network interferences can have significant negative impacts on a company’s balance sheet, which present in the form of business interruption losses due to employees’ inability to perform work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expenditure on cloud computing is projected to increase to $331 billion in 2022, up from $182 billion in 2018, according to Gartner. The number of Internet of Things (IoT) devices doubled from 15 billion to 30 billion between 2015 and 2020 and is expected to grow to 75 billion by 2025, based on research by Statista. This explosive growth in the use of digital technology has significant exposure implications for commercial insurers as well as personal lines insurers of homes and autos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyber security facts in a glance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://enterprise.verizon.com/resources/reports/2019-data-breach-investigations-report.pdf&#34;&gt;94% of malware is delivered via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://enterprise.verizon.com/resources/reports/2019-data-breach-investigations-report.pdf&#34;&gt;Phishing attacks account for more than 8-% of reported security incidents&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.riskiq.com/infographic/evil-internet-minute-2019/&#34;&gt;$17,700 is lost every minute due to phishing attacks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://securityboulevard.com/2019/10/60-of-breaches-in-2019-involved-unpatched-vulnerabilities/&#34;&gt;60 percent of breaches involved vulnerabilities for which a patch was available but not applied&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dellemc.com/en-us/collaterals/unauth/analyst-reports/solutions/dell-bios-security-the-next-frontier-for-endpoint-protection.pdf&#34;&gt;63 percent of companies said their data was potentially compromised within the last twelve months due to a hardware- or silicon-level security breach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.f-secure.com/attack-landscape-h1-2019-iot-smb-traffic-abound/&#34;&gt;Attacks on IoT devices tripled in the first half of 2019.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.trendmicro.com/en_ie/about/newsroom/press-releases/2019/trend-micro-report-reveals-265-growth-fileless-events.html?ClickID=bddygl1ymnsnuvzesflulmydyle6zy1uyvq&#34;&gt;file less attacks grew by 256 percent over the first half of 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ibm.com/security/data-breach?cm_mmc=OSocial_Blog-_-Security_Optimize+the+Security+Program-_-WW_WW-_-CODB2019Blog_ov70891&amp;amp;cm_mmca1=000000NJ&amp;amp;cm_mmca2=10000253&amp;amp;_ga=2.120033672.1876126012.1582597382-1520789394.1582597382&amp;amp;cm_mc_uid=80291023292215825973820&amp;amp;cm_mc_sid_50200000=34095871582696857714&amp;amp;cm_mc_sid_52640000=51761481582696857719&#34;&gt;Data breaches cost enterprises an average of $3.92 million&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cyber coverage – “affirmative” and “non-affirmative”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, after we saw the thread and its impact and meaning, I think the next question should be:  &lt;strong&gt;can companies obtain insurance coverage for cyber-related losses?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is yes, but the way that an insured obtains such coverage could be complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyber insurance comes in two forms:  affirmative cyber liability coverage and non-affirmative or “silent” cyber” coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Affirmative cyber coverage is for cyber perils delineated either in a stand-alone network security and privacy policy or in an endorsement covering data breach or network security failure/attack costs. Such coverage could be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forensic, public relations and credit monitoring costs associated with a breach &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business interruption&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cyber extortion/ransomware payments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replacement, restoration, or re-creation of damaged or lost data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affirmative coverage could also be found in third party liabilities policies. Coverage, as part of this party liability could be through:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Privacy liabilities, such as liabilities and defense costs, fines and penalties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network security liability  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regulatory defense costs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-affirmative, or “silent” cyber coverage refers to cyber losses stemming from traditional property and liability policies. Insureds argue that their policies provide “silent” coverage in different ways, depending on the particular language. Cyber coverage may exist even when a policy does not expressly grant it, when an “all risk” policy does not specifically exclude it, or when an exclusion is ambiguous. As the variety of cyber-attacks continues to grow and develop, so too does the uncertainty surrounding “silent” cyber coverage, leaving the potential for many insureds and other victims of cyber-attacks to seek coverage under a variety of diverse insurance policies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; One of the biggest barriers to the provision of affirmative cover for cyber is the lack of data, models and experience. Insurers are faced with the uncertainty that comes with an emerging risk and the challenges presented by the speed at which the risks are evolving - given that so much of our everyday life is &amp;lsquo;cyber-related&amp;rsquo;, many losses under a policy will inevitably have some form of cyber involvement. This is further complicated by the varied and unpredictable nature and motivation behind cyber-attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This difficulty in determining, defining and quantifying potential exposure has led to gaps in coverage. In the absence of traditional methods appropriate for analyzing cyber risk, insurers should look to experts and white hat hackers – ethical hackers who use their skills to improve security by exposing vulnerabilities – to help identify and evaluate potential cyber exposure buried within non-cyber policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting things into order&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, we saw that the cyber security industry has been developed and grew with security solutions, but also faced security incidents that caused significant losses , but more than that, created uncertainty of whether a policy should react for a cyber  event and indemnify the insured or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UK regulators identified “non-affirmative cyber” loss under traditional P&amp;amp;C insurance as a threat to insurer solvency. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November 2018, Allianz’s Global Corporate and Specialty unit advised that it was updating coverage in 2019 to provide clarity so that physical damage and bodily injury arising from cyber events would generally continue to be covered under corporate, commercial and specialty policies whereas cyber-related “&lt;em&gt;pure financial loss&lt;/em&gt;” without physical damage or injury would be covered under specific cyber policies only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In September 2019, AIG stated that property and casualty policies should be clear about the cyber coverage they provide, and the company announced a shift to affirmative cyber coverages and exclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bankofengland.co.uk/-/media/boe/files/prudential-regulation/letter/2019/cyber-underwriting-risk-follow-up-survey-results&#34;&gt;In a letter published on 30 January 2019&lt;/a&gt;, the Prudential Regulation Authority (PRA) called on Lloyd’s and the insurance industry to act on the issue of &amp;lsquo;silent cyber&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lloyd’s announced &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ciab.com/download/19427/&#34;&gt;its response on 4 July 2019&lt;/a&gt;, stating that “&lt;em&gt;It is the PRA’s view that the potential for a significant ‘silent’ cyber insurance loss is increasing with time. As both ‘silent’ cyber insurance awareness and the frequency of cyber-attacks grow, so does the potential from ‘silent’ cyber exposures. Insurance firms may find it increasingly challenging to argue that all risks or other liability policies did not intend to cover this type of risk given the publicity and awareness of the issue&lt;/em&gt;_ … Lloyd’s view is that it is in the best interests of customers, brokers, and syndicates for all policies to be clear on whether coverage is provided for losses caused by a cyber event. This clarity should be provided by either excluding coverage or by providing affirmative coverage in the (re)insurance policy_.” The Lloyd’s letter also mandating that &lt;em&gt;“all policies provide clarity regarding cyber coverage by either excluding or providing affirmative coverage&lt;/em&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first deadlines covers the property market only, and there were numbers of new clauses issued by the market bodies, which includes the LMS for Lloyds and the IUA for the companies market and other committees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concern of the new clause is that they mainly exclude cyber risk. They distinguish between different types cyber risk, like distinguish between cyber-attack on insured or on a third party which effect on insured and might be different outcome . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, some of the clauses are very hard to follow and are going to lead to confusion, like policies who excludes cyber coverage and then write back specific cyber incident but curve out malicious cyber-attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The challenges of the policy holders&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this change of environment and during the transition period, policy holders, might face new challenges such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No consistent approach among the markets across traditional lines regarding affirming/excluding/sub-limiting cover.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of consistency and market capacity among cyber product solutions in accordance with exclusion introduces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Addressing the gaps in cover that may be created by exclusionary language/sub-limits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limitations in cover introduced by non-cyber insurers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the reasons mentioned above, insured should review their policy terms in-depth, and look for locations where exclusions create gaps in coverage, insureds should consider purchasing cyber cover and look at insurer-created solutions where a cyber policy cannot cover what is excluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Policy holders would consider the following options when they will review the policies provided to them by insurers and might include “silent Cyber” exclusions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reject the exclusion&lt;/strong&gt; – by doing so, the insured will lose Lloyds capacity but at least will have more coverage. So, assume an insured reached the required market capacity in an expected cost, rejection could be an option that the insureds should consider.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Request a less restrictive version&lt;/strong&gt; – this will provide the insured better coverage certainty and retain coverage for some resultant physical perils. From the other hand this choice will put the insured in a situation that some resultants physical perils will still not be covered, and, in most cases, it won’t include coverage for malicious cyber events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accept the exclusion&lt;/strong&gt; – it is probable that an insured will choose this path in cases it will seek for the easiest way to get all required capacity in a reasonable/expected cost. This alternative will likely to exclude more resultant of physical loss then expiated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accept the exclusion and purchased “gap filler” policy&lt;/strong&gt; – this might be the perfect choice for an insured who looks for the perfect available coverage but, it might come with a costly component.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks like, that looking a bit behind the horizon, additional changes must happen in the market to provide more clarity and order for insurers and insureds. The remain holes by mean of uncertainty are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cyber risk definition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cyber risk scope of coverage - malicious intense vs non-malicious.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid coverage overlap as in cyber policies and property damage policies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Virginia Clean Energy Act</title>
      <link>https://nrg.fyi/post/renewable-energy/the-virginia-clean-energy-act/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 15:43:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nrg.fyi/post/renewable-energy/the-virginia-clean-energy-act/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the US EIA (Energy Information Association), current Virginia’s energy production stand on 8.5GW. 53% from Natural Gas, 31% from nuclear power, 10% from coal fueled and nearly 7% from Renewable Energy (RE).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On April 12, 2020 , Governor Ralph Northam signed &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.governor.virginia.gov/newsroom/all-releases/2020/april/headline-856056-en.html&#34;&gt;the Virginia Clean Energy Act (VCEA)&lt;/a&gt;, to accelerate Virginia’s transition to a clean energy environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The VCEA sets Virginia on the path for being 100% carbon free by 2045. By reducing carbon pollution, creating new jobs (estimated by additional 30,000 new jobs), developing the  (RE) economy, improving health outcomes for all Virginians, and saving Virginia families and businesses money on their utility bills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The act has 4 pillars which called the four E’s, that address both the demand and supply of our energy resources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enacting a RPS (Renewable Portfolio Standard) target to make the grid 100% carbon free&lt;/strong&gt; –. RE defined as electricity from wind, solar, falling water, and other in-state resources. The VCEA requires the 2 major utilities in Virginia to become 100% carbon free, it set 2045 as the year target for Dominion Energy and 2050 for ApCo. This RPS target comes also with the benchmarking of 45% renewable in the non-nuclear load by 2030. For Dominion, 75% of all RE must come from the Commonwealth in 2025 and beyond. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The VCEA create the pathway to Zero carbon in few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Emission permits may be issued post 2049&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All coal fired generation should be retired by 2024&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All biomass-fired generation should be retired by 2028&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All other generations that emits carbon should be retired by 2045&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Establishing energy efficiency standards&lt;/strong&gt; – the act intends to create an environment of energy efficiency programs to be “in the public interest”. The act includes a program to reduce energy burden for low-income customers. The act sets an energy efficiency resources standard, requiring third party review of whether energy companies meet savings goals. The VCEA sets energy efficiency renewable standards (EERS) and goals for 2022-2025.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total annual savings (% of Retail Sales) of energy efficiency over a 2019 baseline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dominion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ApCo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.25%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.5%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2023&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.5%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2024&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.5%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2025&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advances offshore wind and other RE resources&lt;/strong&gt;– the act defines that offshore wind generation is in “in the public interest”. The VCEA establishes offshore wind as a substantial portion of the RPS as offshore wind comes online and deploys 5,300 MW by 2034 making Virginia a leader in offshore wind state generators. It also includes labor provisions to require the use of the local labor. For Distribution solar, it establishes rooftop solar as a portion of the RP up to 1% of the annual goals beginning in 2021. The VCEA sets targets for energy storage of 3,100 MW of energy storage by 2035, including 2,700MW for Dominion and 400MW for ApCo. It also requires 10% of energy storage to be deployed directly “behind the meter” for power backups at hospitals, government facilities, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a snapshot of the RE requirement from Dominion and ApCp, through 2035&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year of petition to the SCC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Onshore RE (Dominion) MW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Onshore RE (ApCo) MW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2023&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2024&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2027&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2030&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2035&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6,100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year of petition to the SCC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storage (Dominion) MW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storage (ApCo) MW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2035&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,700&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year in service&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Offshore (Dominion) MW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Offshore (ApCo) MW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2028&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,500-3,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2034&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,100-2,600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;35% of all RE mw shown in the table above must be third party owned and operated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The utilities can use RECS generated by these resources to fulfill their RPS obligation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Storage targets are technology agnostic. The primary limitation is that no one storage facilities may comprise over then 500MW of the utilities target with the exception of 1 storage facility of 800MW in Dominion&amp;rsquo;s territory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expanding Distributed Clean Power Generation&lt;/strong&gt; – The VCEA set new rules for the Distribution Generation (DG):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1% of the RPS’s will be allocated for DG. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raises the Net Energy Metering (NEM) projects cap of the utility projects from 1% to 6%. In addition, not after 2024 (for Dominion) and 2025 (for ApCo), the SCC (Virginia State Corporation Commission) should revisit and set new tariffs for the NEM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raises the ceiling size of individual DG projects from 1MW to 3MW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raises to cap of the PPA from 50MW to 1,000MW, for Dominion (split 50-50 between jurisdictions such as school and municipalities, and 500MW to non-jurisdictional) and 40MW to ApCo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Resources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Rh2VyLuktxQ#action=share&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Rh2VyLuktxQ#action=share&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ccanactionfund.org/media/Virginia-Clean-Economy-Act-update-factsheet.pdf&#34;&gt;https://ccanactionfund.org/media/Virginia-Clean-Economy-Act-update-factsheet.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
