<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IRA on NRG.fyi  Fuel Your Knowledge</title>
    <link>https://nrg.fyi/tags/ira/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IRA on NRG.fyi  Fuel Your Knowledge</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nrg.fyi/tags/ira/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The IRA benefit to the American Economy</title>
      <link>https://nrg.fyi/post/tax/the-virginia-clean-energy-act/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nrg.fyi/post/tax/the-virginia-clean-energy-act/</guid>
      <description>The Inflation Reduction Act&amp;rsquo;s investments are bearing fruit by creating good-paying jobs, strengthening our energy security, tackling climate change, and improving services the IRS provides to taxpayers. As a part of President Biden&amp;rsquo;s broader Investing in America agenda, Treasury will continue to collect and share data, analysis, and stories about how the IRA is aiding American families and workers, driving investment toward underserved communities as well as to new technologies and markets, and ensuring economic fairness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tax Credit transactions and their risk associated</title>
      <link>https://nrg.fyi/post/financing/tax-credit-transactions-and-their-risk-associated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nrg.fyi/post/financing/tax-credit-transactions-and-their-risk-associated/</guid>
      <description>The Inflation Reduction Act&amp;rsquo;s investments are bearing fruit by creating good-paying jobs, strengthening our energy security, tackling climate change, and improving services the IRS provides to taxpayers.&#xA;The IRA development in terms of tax credits, included:&#xA;Extension of the production tax credit (PTC) and the investment tax credit (ITC) for electricity generated from wind, solar and certain other renewable resources. Expansion of the resources eligible for the PTC and ITC, including by allowing the ITC for energy storage technologies such as batteries.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
