<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>solar on NRG.fyi  Fuel Your Knowledge</title>
    <link>https://nrg.fyi/tags/solar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in solar on NRG.fyi  Fuel Your Knowledge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nrg.fyi/tags/solar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Up Private Finance for Clean Energy in Emerging and Developing Economies</title>
      <link>https://nrg.fyi/post/financing/private-finance-for-clean-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nrg.fyi/post/financing/private-finance-for-clean-energy/</guid>
      <description>This intend to be a summary post of the “Scaling up Private Finance for Clean Energy in Emerging and Developing Economies” published by the IEA and IFC The Emerging Markets and Developing Economics (EMDEs) group contains the following territories: Africa, Developing Europe, Eurasia, Latin America, the Middle East and South and Southeast Asia.
In EMDEs there are 775 million people that lack access to electricity and 2.4B that lack access to clean cooking fuels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Main EU Markets for co-located projects</title>
      <link>https://nrg.fyi/post/energy-storage/main-eu-markets-for-co-located-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nrg.fyi/post/energy-storage/main-eu-markets-for-co-located-projects/</guid>
      <description>UK
The main drivers for implements hybrid projects in the UK are:
 Advanced grid services: The UK comprises the most advanced standalone battery storage market in Europe, having pioneered since 2017 through the proliferation of grid-services. Mature Industry: Due to vast commercialization expertise, the industry is the most welcoming when it comes to innovation such as co-located assets and Hybrid PPAs.  The UK is Europe’s largest energy storage market – by far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contractual arrangement in Hybrid PPA’s agreements.</title>
      <link>https://nrg.fyi/post/ppa/contractual-arrangement-in-hybrid-ppas-agreements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nrg.fyi/post/ppa/contractual-arrangement-in-hybrid-ppas-agreements/</guid>
      <description>There are several ways in which a Hybrid PPA can work. Just like the technical set up of each co-located project, there is no one size fits all when it comes to the commercialization aspect. It always comes down to investment goals, risk appetite and the capabilities when it comes to trading assets of each asset owner.
Renewable PPA &amp;amp; Storage Capacity agreement (CSA)/Optimization agreement
In this scenario, the hybrid arrangement comprises two contracts:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Components driving PPA price and their risks.</title>
      <link>https://nrg.fyi/post/ppa/components-driving-ppa-price-and-their-risks./</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nrg.fyi/post/ppa/components-driving-ppa-price-and-their-risks./</guid>
      <description>PPA structures are evolving, and the challenge of Hybrid PPAs lies behind understanding and quantifying the benefits of flexibility, and how it’s reflected in the pricing. The risk profile of the asset is the core determinant of its fair value. And since energy storage changes the risk profile of the generation part, this would need to be reflected in the price.
To understand what’s driving the Hybrid PAP pricing, it would be better to go through how benchmark PPA prices are modelled, and the risk components driving the fair value of the energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future energy storage and distribution</title>
      <link>https://nrg.fyi/post/energy-storage/future-energy-storage-and-distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nrg.fyi/post/energy-storage/future-energy-storage-and-distribution/</guid>
      <description>It is no longer a secret, nor a great insight, that we are in a revolutionary era in terms of the energy industry. Many technologies , greener and cheaper are implemented , a lot of assets we uses are being electrified (EV&amp;rsquo;s , heating solution) and more and energy , in general becomes more of commodity than an production resource.
With that development, new challenges and limitations arise and create risks for industrial, commercial, and residential uses and processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Value of Energy storage in Europe</title>
      <link>https://nrg.fyi/post/energy-storage/the-value-of-energy-storage-in-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nrg.fyi/post/energy-storage/the-value-of-energy-storage-in-europe/</guid>
      <description>Energy storage has been deemed one of the missing links of the energy transition for quite some time now. After the vast deployment of standalone storage assets, which tirelessly (and swiftly) respond for duty when the grid needs it, the long-awaited next phase of renewables-plus storage is finally approaching the mainstream!
The term ‘renewables-plus-storage colocation’ has climbed the ladder in the renewable’s vocabulary, particularly in the merchant renewables sphere. But combining two business models requires the resolution of multiple riddles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The energy Security Scenario</title>
      <link>https://nrg.fyi/post/global-energy/the-energy-security-scenario/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nrg.fyi/post/global-energy/the-energy-security-scenario/</guid>
      <description>This is a summary of the Energy Security Scenarios report made by Shell.
Shell created 3 different energy scenarios - Waves, Islands and Sky 1.5. Each of these was built around possible approaches to climate change action as the world emerged from the COVID-19 pandemic.
Waves - Waves assumed that society would prioritize repairing the economy. In Waves this focus on wealth pushes other societal and environmental pressures into the background, until their relative neglect provokes backlash reactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Virginia Clean Energy Act</title>
      <link>https://nrg.fyi/post/renewable-energy/the-virginia-clean-energy-act/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 15:43:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nrg.fyi/post/renewable-energy/the-virginia-clean-energy-act/</guid>
      <description>According to the US EIA (Energy Information Association), current Virginia’s energy production stand on 8.5GW. 53% from Natural Gas, 31% from nuclear power, 10% from coal fueled and nearly 7% from Renewable Energy (RE).
On April 12, 2020 , Governor Ralph Northam signed the Virginia Clean Energy Act (VCEA), to accelerate Virginia’s transition to a clean energy environment.
The VCEA sets Virginia on the path for being 100% carbon free by 2045.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
